Saint Roger Bountsebe Eboueme, M.S., B.A.

About: As a recent graduate with a Master of Science in Applied Economics from the University of San Francisco, my expertise lies in crop yield prediction, machine learning, and weather prediction. With a solid foundation in Computer Science and a farmer background, I am equipped with skills to empower farmers through diverse channels using data.

EDUCATION

The University of San Francisco

Sept 2021 - May 2023

M.S, Applied Economics

San Francisco

Coursework: Econometrics, Statistics, Institutions Markets Platforms, Experiment and Causal Inference, Data Visualization, Data Management with SQL, Hypothesis Testing, Data mining/Cleaning.

London School of Economics

June 2019 – Aug 2019

Coursework: Financial Markets and Global Economy, Money and Banking, Macroeconomics

London, England

Hiram College

Aug 2016 - May 2020

B.A, Economics and Applied Computer Science

Hiram, Ohio

Coursework: Python, Javascript, Java, Data Structure, Algorithms and Design, SQL, Python for Data Science.

Technical Skills: Python, SQL, Java, Machine Learning, Regression Analysis, R, Google Earth Engine, Scikit-Learn, Pandas, ArcGIS Pro, Stats Models, Forecasting,

Certifications: Foundations in Data Science, Critical Thinking and Problem Solving, Cross Cultural Communication.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Math Instructor/Machine Learning Instructor - Sacred Heart Cathedral Preparatory, San Francisco

Jan 2023 - Current

- Used data visualization to identify students in need, this led to an increase in class average grade by 10%.
- Mentored and coached 50 students from three different class grades
- Planned and taught basics of machine learning to a group of 10 students; Train, evaluate and optimize models.

Information Technology (IT) Analyst - Sacred Heart Cathedral Preparatory, San Francisco

Sept 2022 - Current

- Partnered with third party providers such as AWS, Google Suite, Cisco to optimize digital platforms, streamlining user support and efficiently resolving technical issues.
- Engaged in continuous professional development activities to enhance corporate IT capabilities.
- Utilized Python to scrape data from third party websites and employed SQL to transform data into a consumable format.

Satellite Data Research Analyst - The University of San Francisco

Jan 2022 – Oct 2022

- Utilized Python to clean and analyze World Bank household survey data and created panel data for further analysis.
- Used weather and geolocation data from google earth engine merged with survey data to create a model.
- Applied different Machine Learning Models to predict individual farmers yield: Random Forest performed best.

Soft Skills: Analytics Skills, Problem Solving, Critical Thinking, Strategic Thinking, Leadership Skills, Adaptability, Project Management, Prioritization and Decision Making, Teamwork, Cross-Team Communication, Market Research.

PROJECTS

Master Degree Capstone Project

May 2023

- Used Fixed Effect to estimate the impact of market access on farmer's revenue in Nigeria, showing fluency in R Python.
- Although not significant, market access has an effect on farmers' sales. This effect varies from rural to urban area.

Insurance for Coffee Farmers - Coffee Yield Prediction

September 2022

- I used the following models to predict yield: OLS, Elastic Net, Neural Net and Random Forest(r-square: 0.68).
- Used GridSearchCV for parameter tuning and Two Stage Prediction to improve Yield Prediction with Python.

TAGRID CO-Founder and Executive Director

• Tagrid is a Non Profit that works with farmers to improve their socio-economic status while promoting sustainability.